{
	"name": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary",
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "A simple joint where the bony projections of the scapula and the clavicle meet at the top of the shoulder.",
			"back": "acromioclavicular joint"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "An injury in which part of the body is completely severed.",
			"back": "amputation"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "A pearly white layer of specialized cartilage covering the articular surfaces (contact surfaces on the ends) of bones in synovial joints.",
			"back": "articular cartilage"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "The heel bone.",
			"back": "calcaneus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "Any break in a bone in which the overlying skin is not broken.",
			"back": "closed fracture"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "Swelling in a confined space that produces dangerous pressure; may cut off blood flow or damage sensitive tissue.",
			"back": "compartment syndrome"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "A grating or grinding sensation or sound caused by fractured bone ends or joints rubbing together.",
			"back": "crepitus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "Disruption of a joint in which ligaments are damaged and the bone ends are no longer in contact.",
			"back": "dislocation"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "A fracture in which bone fragments are separated from one another, producing deformity in the limb.",
			"back": "displaced fracture"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "A buildup of blood beneath the skin that produces a characteristic blue or black discoloration as the result of an injury.",
			"back": "ecchymosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "Movement that occurs in a bone at a point where there is no joint, indicating a fracture; also called free movement.",
			"back": "false motion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "The fiber-like connective tissue that covers arteries, veins, tendons, and ligaments.",
			"back": "fascia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "The smaller of the two bones that form the lower leg, located on the lateral side.",
			"back": "fibula"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "A break in the continuity of a bone.",
			"back": "fracture"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "The part of the scapula that joins with the humeral head to form the glenohumeral joint.",
			"back": "glenoid fossa"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-16",
			"front": "Blood in the urine.",
			"back": "hematuria"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-17",
			"front": "The place where two bones come into contact.",
			"back": "joint"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-18",
			"front": "Bands of fibrous tissue that connect bones to bones. These tissuess support and strengthen a joint.",
			"back": "ligaments"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-19",
			"front": "A simple crack in the bone that has not caused the bone to move from its normal anatomic position; also called a hairline fracture.",
			"back": "nondisplaced fracture"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-20",
			"front": "Any break in a bone in which the overlying skin has been broken.",
			"back": "open fracture"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-21",
			"front": "A device to splint the bony pelvis to reduce hemorrhage from bone ends, venous disruption, and pain.",
			"back": "pelvic binder"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-22",
			"front": "Tenderness that is sharply localized at the site of the injury, found by gently palpating along the bone with the tip of one finger.",
			"back": "point tenderness"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-23",
			"front": "A hand position in which the wrist is slightly dorsiflexed and all finger joints are moderately flexed.",
			"back": "position of function"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-24",
			"front": "To return a dislocated joint or fractured bone to its normal position; to set.",
			"back": "reduce"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-25",
			"front": "The space between the abdominal cavity and the posterior abdominal wall, containing the kidneys, certain large vessels, and parts of the gastrointestinal tract.",
			"back": "retroperitoneal space"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-26",
			"front": "The major nerve to the lower extremities; controls much of muscle function in the leg and sensation in most of the leg and foot.",
			"back": "sciatic nerve"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-27",
			"front": "A bandage or material that helps to support the weight of an injured upper extremity.",
			"back": "sling"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-28",
			"front": "A flexible or rigid device used to protect and maintain the position of an injured extremity.",
			"back": "splint"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-29",
			"front": "A joint injury involving damage to supporting ligaments, and sometimes partial or temporary dislocation of bone ends.",
			"back": "sprain"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-30",
			"front": "Stretching or tearing of a muscle; also called a muscle pull.",
			"back": "strain"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-31",
			"front": "A bandage that passes around the chest to secure an injured arm to the chest.",
			"back": "swathe"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-32",
			"front": "The shinbone; the larger of the two bones of the lower leg.",
			"back": "tibia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-33",
			"front": "The bleeding control method used when a wound continues to bleed despite the use of direct pressure; useful if a patient is bleeding severely from a partial or complete amputation.",
			"back": "tourniquet"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-34",
			"front": "Longitudinal force applied to a structure.",
			"back": "traction"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-32-tag-vocabulary-card-35",
			"front": "The area of potentially damaged soft tissue, adjacent nerves, and blood vessels surrounding an injury to a bone or a joint.",
			"back": "zone of injury"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-32",
		"label": "Chapter 32"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}